<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>MailArchive</web>
  <name>Mail Archive Troubleshooting</name>
  <language/>
  <defaultLanguage/>
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>xwiki:XWiki.Admin</creator>
  <creationDate>1394137161000</creationDate>
  <parent>MailArchive.Mail Archive Documentation</parent>
  <author>xwiki:XWiki.Admin</author>
  <customClass/>
  <contentAuthor>xwiki:XWiki.Admin</contentAuthor>
  <date>1393179252000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1393179252000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.1</version>
  <title>Troubleshooting section</title>
  <defaultTemplate/>
  <validationScript/>
  <comment/>
  <minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
  <hidden/>
  <content>{{toc/}}

= Connection to mail server =

== Connection testing ==
Remember to browse to the server configuration page, where you can easily test the connection. Usually testing should provide indications of what the problem is, sometimes you will have to check the logs for exceptions, to find out. Some common problems are listed below.

== javax.net.ssl.SSLHandshakeException: sun.security.validator.ValidatorException: PKIX path building failed: sun.security.provider.certpath.SunCertPathBuilderException: unable to find valid certification path to requested target ==

If you get this exception, it means that your mail server certificate must be added to the keystore of the VM used to launch XWiki server.

You can follow the instructions from this page, or use google to find more:

http://www.java-samples.com/showtutorial.php?tutorialid=210

Notes:
- If you are under Windows 7, remember to launch command DOS window with administrative rights.
- Take care to update the correct JRE used by xwiki.
- Restart xwiki after adding the certificate for it to take effect.

Alternatively, you can check option on server page to automatically trust SSL certificates for a specific account - but this is not recommended.

= Connection to a Store =

== What is a store and how to configure one in the mail archive ? ==

It's a text file containing emails, in so-called "mbox" format. In usual email vocabulary, a Store can be defined by a folder, sub-folders (in filesystem) relate to Folders (in email account), as do mbox file itself. Emails are contained in mbox files.

For example:
c:/myboxes/mailing-lists/
  xwiki/
    devs.mbox
    users.mbox
  jenkins.mbox

You could then configure a store for jenkins with location "c:/myboxes/mailing-lists" folder "jenkins.mbox".
Or a store for xwiki users with location "c:/myboxes/mailing-lists/xwiki" folder "users.mbox".
Or alternatively location "c:/myboxes/mailing-lists" folder "xwiki/users.mbox". 

Mbox format is a historic file format, for example it can be generated by Google takeout, Mozilla Thunderbird (it's its native format), most mailing-lists archives on the www, ...

== Not enough memory ==

The underlying library in charge of parsing mbox files can easily use large quantities of memory. As it mainly depends on the size of the mbox file, it is recommended to split this mbox file in several smaller files (for information, I was successful with 1700m of Xmx for XWiki JVM, and mbox files of about 300m).
Mozilla knowledge Base has a [[nice and useful article&gt;&gt;http://kb.mozillazine.org/Edit_large_mbox_files]] about how to edit and split mbox files.

== Parsing errors ==

Mbox format has several variants. Underlying parsing library is configured to be the less "strict" possible, but it can still happen that format is unparseable. It was successfully tested with mbox format generated by Google takeout.
Usually, issues can be solved by editing the mbox file with a (good) text editor, then doing some appropriate replacements. For example, mbox files generated by Thunderbird sometimes do not escape properly "from" lines.
Do not hesitate to post a question to the xwiki users mailing-list in case of annoying mboxes.



</content>
</xwikidoc>
